export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. A person with a positive self-image",
A: "believes in himself/herself",
B: "does his/her work",
C: "loves to argue with others",
D: "takes delight to compete",
answer: "A. believes in himself/herself",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. One benefits Ghana derives from her membership of the Commonweal the of Nations is",
A: "education and training",
B: "effective supervision of the civil service",
C: "legal representation at the International Court of Justice",
D: "stabilization of the local currency",
answer: "A. education and training",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. In Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs, a footballer who realizes his dream of playing for a foreign team will be described as having satisfied his",
A: "physiological need",
B: "self-actualization need",
C: "self-esteem need",
D: "social need",
answer: "B. self-actualization need",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. A feature of democratic governance is",
A: "development of good international relations",
B: "rapid improvement of the economy",
C: "the emergence of strong leadership",
D: "the existence rule of law",
answer: "D. the existence rule of law",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Members of the commonwealth of Nationals were once governed by",
A: "Canada",
B: "Germany",
C: "Great Britain",
D: "Portugal",
answer: "C. Great Britain",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. Traditional festivals are important in Ghana because they serve as",
A: "avenues for chiefs to display their wealth",
B: "avenues for outdooring new born babies",
C: "occasions for chiefs to receive royalties",
D: "occasions for promoting social solidarity",
answer: "D. occasions for promoting social solidarity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. When people are forced to leave their country as a result of conflict, they become",
A: "detainees",
B: "dissidents",
C: "mercenaries",
D: "refugees",
answer: "D. refugees",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Ghana has not been able to exploit her natural resources fully due to",
A: "excessive bureaucracy",
B: "high rate of inflation",
C: "high rate of population growth",
D: "lack of technical know-how",
answer: "D. lack of technical know-how",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Any legitimate, lawful and socially acceptable act one performs to earn a living is",
A: "bureaucracy",
B: "contribution",
C: "cooperation",
D: "work",
answer: "D. work",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. An independent judiciary in Ghana is necessary because it",
A: "allows the government to have its own way",
B: "ensures equality in the salaries and wages of workers",
C: "protects the fundamental rights of the citizens",
D: "provides the people with the right information",
answer: "C. protects the fundamental rights of the citizens",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. One major activity that threatens the physical environment in Ghana is",
A: "beach sand extraction",
B: "compost farming",
C: "land reclamation",
D: "recycling of waste",
answer: "A. beach sand extraction",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. Knowledge of the effect of the vicious cycle of rapid population growth enables people to",
A: "exhibit national consciousness",
B: "give birth many children",
C: "pay their taxes promptly",
D: "plan well for future",
answer: "A. exhibit national consciousness",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. Rights of citizens of Ghana can curtailed when there is",
A: "a general election",
B: "a national population census",
C: "a new government in place",
D: "an outbreak of epidemic",
answer: "D. an outbreak of epidemic",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. The most important stage in the process of contracting marriage in the Ghanaian society is",
A: "adoption of children",
B: "celebration of puberty rites",
C: "consummation of the union",
D: "knocking at the door",
answer: "D. knocking at the door",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. To increase productivity, people in leadership positions much",
A: "employ only relations",
B: "enhance their salaries",
C: "create effective channels of communication",
D: "create more job opportunities",
answer: "C. create effective channels of communication",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. One characteristics of people who achieve self-actualization is that, they",
A: "accept all views",
B: "excel in academic",
C: "seek self-recognition",
D: "stick to their beliefs",
answer: "D. stick to their beliefs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. It is necessary for couples to respect each other’s reproductive rights because",
A: "men are considered family heads",
B: "they are equal partners in marriage",
C: "they need many children",
D: "women resist attempts to be intimidated",
answer: "B. they are equal partners in marriage",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. One consequence of marriage break-ups is",
A: "disagreement between the couple",
B: "that child care becomes he responsibility of only one partner",
C: "the inability of the husband to maintain the family",
D: "the irresponsible behavior of one of the couple",
answer: "B. that child care becomes he responsibility of only one partner",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. One benefit of sustained development in Ghana is that it",
A: "ensures saving of funds for other projects",
B: "enhances the improvement of human resource",
C: "ensures the effective prioritization of projects",
D: "promotes the cultivation of positive attitude to work",
answer: "A. ensures saving of funds for other projects",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Reproductive health education for adolescents aims mainly at helping them to",
A: "cope with their emotional problems",
B: "increase their physical fitness level",
C: "increase their social contacts",
D: "obtain good grades in school",
answer: "A. cope with their emotional problems",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. One way of sustaining marriage in the Ghanaian society is for the couple to",
A: "amass wealth",
B: "be faithful to each other",
C: "practice family planning",
D: "take part in family meetings",
answer: "B. be faithful to each other",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. International cooperation is based on the principle of",
A: "inter-dependence",
B: "neutrality and peace",
C: "self-reliance",
D: "self-sufficiency",
answer: "A. inter-dependence",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. One objective of the New Partnership for Africa’s Development (NEPAD) is to",
A: "eradicate poverty",
B: "improve trade",
C: "manage public revenue",
D: "promote production",
answer: "A. eradicate poverty",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. One effect of global warming on the environment is the",
A: "burning of fossil fuel",
B: "increase in agricultural production",
C: "increase in industrial pollution",
D: "rise in sea levels and flooding",
answer: "D. rise in sea levels and flooding",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. A leader who takes advantage of his old age and experience to determine policies and decisions fora group is",
A: "autocratic",
B: "democratic",
C: "laissez faire",
D: "paternalistic",
answer: "D. paternalistic",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. The main aim of education is to",
A: "enable the individual acquire certificates",
B: "enable the individual secure job",
C: "equip the individual with requisite skills",
D: "prepare the individual to participate in governance",
answer: "C. equip the individual with requisite skills",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. A condition for the smooth functioning of the principle of rule of law is",
A: "Option 1",
B: "Option 2",
C: "Option 3",
D: "Option 4",
answer: "D. the assumed innocence of the accused before conviction",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. A significant measure taken in sustaining growth and development in Ghana is",
A: "acquisition of certificates in liberal education",
B: "improvement in skills of workers",
C: "promotion of higher population growth",
D: "provision of better incentives for workers",
answer: "B. improvement in skills of workers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. The main goal of national development effort is to",
A: "ensure the acquisition of foreign aid",
B: "create an elite society",
C: "make cities more attractive",
D: "raise citizens’ living standards",
answer: "D. raise citizens’ living standards",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. To resolve parent-child conflict effectively, the parent must",
A: "be over protective",
B: "be very strict",
C: "listen to the child",
D: "punish the child",
answer: "C. listen to the child",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Which of the following business enterprise has the capacity to raise huge capital by floating shares,",
A: "Co-operative societies",
B: "Joint Stock Companies",
C: "Partnership",
D: "Public Corporations",
answer: "B. Joint Stock Companies",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. The best way to resolve conflicts in the Ghanaian society is through",
A: "consensus-building",
B: "harsh sanctions",
C: "peaceful demonstrations",
D: "the law courts",
answer: "A. consensus-building",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Cultural practices such as widowhood rites and the ‘trokosi’ system need to be abolished mainly because",
A: "the United Nations said so",
B: "they are practiced only in remote communities",
C: "they are too old-fashioned",
D: "they violate human rights",
answer: "D. they violate human rights",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. Economic activities found in most parts of Ghana are dictated by the",
A: "effects of globalization",
B: "level of technology",
C: "physical environment",
D: "trend of migration",
answer: "C. physical environment",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Peace building in the Ghanaian society can best be promoted through",
A: "demonstrations",
B: "the imposition of curfew",
C: "the use of the army",
D: "tolerance",
answer: "D. tolerance",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The ultimate result of positive work attitude is",
A: "competent human resources",
B: "improvement in technology",
C: "increased output",
D: "hard work",
answer: "C. increased output",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. One effect of excessive logging and lumbering in Ghana is",
A: "cash crop production",
B: "industrialization",
C: "loss of fertility",
D: "re-afforestation",
answer: "C. loss of fertility",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. One characteristic of autocratic leadership is that",
A: "the leader is chosen by majority of the people",
B: "the leader takes decisions on behalf of the followers",
C: "there is lack of communication between the leader and the followers",
D: "power is shared equally between the leader and the followers",
answer: "B. the leader takes decisions on behalf of the followers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. The process of bringing up and looking after children to be useful citizens is",
A: "education",
B: "parenthood",
C: "parenting",
D: "socialization",
answer: "C. parenting",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. The government of Ghana undertakes industrialization in order to",
A: "diversify the economy",
B: "control internal trade",
C: "increase the cost of production",
D: "improve bilateral trade",
answer: "A. diversify the economy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. A characteristic of a buoyant economy is the existence of",
A: "high birth rate",
B: "high infant mortality",
C: "low birth rate",
D: "low level of literacy",
answer: "C. low birth rate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. Most HIV/AIDS patients do not come out for treatment because",
A: "the society stigmatizes them",
B: "there are no hospitals to treat them",
C: "they believe it is a spiritual disease",
D: "treatment is very expensive",
answer: "A. the society stigmatizes them",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. The process by which society is transformed to enable it meet new challenges is referred to as",
A: "education",
B: "empowerment",
C: "socialization",
D: "social change",
answer: "D. social change",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. A situation where a person hides his/her true identity and pretends to be what he/she Is not is referred to as",
A: "false identity",
B: "false order",
C: "image hiding",
D: "second image",
answer: "A. false identity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. The negative aspect of culture has the tendency to",
A: "change society’s festivals",
B: "influence only the illiterate",
C: "promote urban-rural migration",
D: "reduce human dignity",
answer: "D. reduce human dignity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. A major characteristic of informal education is that",
A: "much of the learning is unsystematic",
B: "it is carried out for people who are in business",
C: "it is carried out in organized institution",
D: "it is well structured",
answer: "A. much of the learning is unsystematic",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. According to Abraham Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs Theory, man’s basic needs are",
A: "self-esteem",
B: "physiological",
C: "self-actualization",
D: "social",
answer: "B. physiological",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. Which of the following factor does not help an individual to develop self-confidence?",
A: "Cultural beliefs",
B: "Low satisfaction of needs",
C: "self-determination",
D: "The type of training",
answer: "B. Low satisfaction of needs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. A state of complete physical, mental and social well-being with regard to the reproductive system is",
A: "adolescent chastity",
B: "adolescent morality",
C: "reproductive health",
D: "reproductive rights",
answer: "C. reproductive health",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. Generation of power from water and the sun arc indications of",
A: "increased productivity",
B: "man’s control of the environment",
C: "national needs and aspiration",
D: "the wonder of nature",
answer: "B. man’s control of the environment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]